One strategy that is often used in hybrid approaches for
在行为分类的混合法中 经常使用的一个策略是
behavior classification is to combine a classifier with a filter.
把分类器和过滤器相结合
We will show why.
下面我们看看为何这么做
For now we will introduce a simple behavior classifier, Naive Bayes.
现在 我们会引入一个简单的行为分类器 - Naive Bayes
Let's walk through how Naive Bayes works by using an example.
我们通过一个例子来看 Naive Bayes 是如何工作的
We are going to reason on gender using
例如 我们想要通过两种特征变量 - 身高和体重 - 的统计数值
statistics of two feature variables; height and weight.
来推测某人的性别
As an output we want the probability that
在我们输入身高和体重数据后
a person is male or female given their height or weight.
作为输出 我们想得到某人是男是女的几率大小
In a Naive Bayes classifier,
在一个 Naive Bayes 分类器中
the probability of being male given height and weight is
给定身高和体重后 如果要计算结果为男的几率
just the probability of the height given male times the probability of
那么具体算法是 先用该身高为男的几率乘以该体重为男的几率
that weight given male multiplied by the prior probability of being male something
然后再乘以结果为男的先验几率
close to point five divided by
这个先验几率是一个0.5左右的值
the probability of the height and weight in the overall population.
然后再除以给定的身高体重值在总样本中的几率
The reason why this algorithm is called Naive Bayes is
此算法之所以称为 Naive Bayes
that it assumes that all features contribute independently.
是因为它假定所有的特征值独立地起作用
And while in reality there is correlation between height and weight in people.
但在现实生活中 人的身高和体重之间是有相关性的
In practice the independence assumption often winds up working.
实践中 这种独立性假定经常干扰我们的工作
The equation about can be simplified.
这个方程式可以被简化
This term will affect both probabilities male and female in the same way.
这个项会以同样方式影响男和女的几率
It is just a normalization factor.
它仅仅是一个归一化因子
This means we can first compute this part of the equation
这样的话 我们可以先计算方程的这一部分
both for male and female and then compute the final probability
作为计算男女性别几率的通用步骤
of male given height and rate and probability of female
然后再计算最终的几率
given height male by normalizing them to make them sum to one.
然后将这些值规格化 使他们的和为1
The problem is all about finding these terms.
问题所在就是找出这些项
Often, we can assume it goes in distribution for the feature variables.
经常地 我们可以假定这个问题和特征变量的概率分布有关
If you make this assumption the algorithm is then called Gaussian Naive Bayes.
如果假定该分布为高斯分布 那么该算法就称为高斯 Naive Bayes 算法
So in practice, implementing a good Gaussian Naive Bayes classifier is all about one,
因此 在实践中 要实现一个不错的高斯 Naive Bayes 分类器 我们只需要做一件事情
selecting the correct feature variables for the classification problem.
那就是 为分类问题选择合适的特征变量
This is vary can use some human intuition combined with
这其实可以靠人类的直觉
feature selection algorithms to anticipate what
再结合特征选择算法
factors are relevant for a given classification situation.
来测出对于给定分类情形 何种因子与其具有相关性
I call her for example would not be very useful in predicting gender.
比如 女性称呼语 her 在预测性别时候用处不大
And two identifying some good means and variances for different classes.
我们要做的第二件事情是 为不同的类标识出良好的平均数和变异数
And we can either guess these numbers or we can look at lots of data to learn them.
我们可以猜测这些数字 也可以通过大量数据去学习
For example, if you have access to lots of data
举个例子 如果你可以访问
about how drivers handle intersections and if you define
有关司机在交叉路口如何操作的大量数据
some good features which indicating tension's of drivers you could use
而且 你定义了一些有效的特征 这些特征指示出司机的紧张程度
Naive Bayes to compute the probability of each behavior at each time step.
那么 你就可以使用 Naive Bayes 来计算每个时间点上各种行为的可能性
For the trajectory prediction part.
在轨迹预测部分
You could use one of the following models we talked about earlier.
你可以使用如下的算法之一 这些算法我们之前都讨论过